const quizQuestions8en = [{
    question:"Why is the covered electrode said to have a lower deposition capacity (kg/h, for example) than continuous wire feed processes?",
    answers: ["Basically, because the Duty Cycle (Operation Factor) is lower.",
    "Because it has a longer energized electrode length, limiting the applicable current density.",
    "Because it uses Constant Current type power source (which limits the applicable current).",
    "Because this welding is manual."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The main function of compressed air in carbon arc gouging is to:",
    answers: ["facilitate arc opening;",
    "protect the fusion zone;",
    "remove porosity;",
    "remove molten metal."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The tungsten electrode tip wears out quickly in TIG welding due to:",
    answers: ["an excessively high shielding gas flow;",
    "a too large nozzle cup;",
    "a contamination of the electrode tip;",
    "an excessively high no-load voltage;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The tungsten electrode tip wears out quickly in TIG welding due to:",
    answers: ["an excessively high shielding gas flow;",
    "a too large nozzle cup;",
    "an excessively high no-load voltage;",
    "an improper sharpening of the tungsten electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be considered when selecting a type of carbon steel electrode wire for the GMAW (MIG/MAG) process?",
    answers: ["Oxidation potential of the shielding gas used.",
    "Base metal thickness.",
    "Welding position.",
    "Welding technique (pulling or pushing / backhand or forehand)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following devices or techniques would be most advantageous for TIG (GTAW) welding of precision parts?",
    answers: ["A gas lens.",
    "Pulsed arc function.",
    "A device for additional protection (“trailer”).",
    "A high frequency ignition unit."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is one of the functions of submerged arc welding flux:",
    answers: ["to provide the elements to increase the stability of the arc;",
    "to provide iron powder to increase the deposition rate;",
    "to protect the environment from welding fumes;",
    "to protect the environment against radiation from the welding arc."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is one of the functions of submerged arc welding flux:",
    answers: ["to provide iron powder to increase the deposition rate;",
    "to form slag with certain physical and chemical properties to control the appearance and shape of the weld bead;",
    "to protect the environment from welding fumes;",
    "to protect the environment against radiation from the welding arc."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is one of the functions of submerged arc welding flux:",
    answers: ["to provide iron powder to increase the deposition rate;",
    "to protect the environment from welding fumes;",
    "to protect the weld pool metal from contamination by the atmosphere;",
    "to protect the environment against radiation from the welding arc."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following gases helps to promote the cleaning action on aluminium when using TIG welding (GTAW)?",
    answers: ["Argon+Helium.",
    "Argon+Hydrogen.",
    "Helium.",
    "Argon."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What influences the operability (usefulness) of covered electrodes in out of position welding?",
    answers: ["The used current value.",
    "The generation of fumes by the electrode.",
    "The generation of spatter by the electrode.",
    "A possible difficulty in arc opening."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What influences the operability (usefulness) of covered electrodes in out of position welding?",
    answers: ["The generation of fumes by the electrode.",
    "The electrode diameter and coating thickness.",
    "The generation of spatter by the electrode.",
    "A possible difficulty in arc opening."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What influences the operability (usefulness) of covered electrodes in out of position welding?",
    answers: ["The generation of fumes by the electrode.",
    "The generation of spatter by the electrode.",
    "The arc length.",
    "A possible difficulty in arc opening."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What influences the operability (usefulness) of covered electrodes in out of position welding?",
    answers: ["The generation of fumes by the electrode.",
    "The generation of spatter by the electrode.",
    "A possible difficulty in arc opening.",
    "The coating type."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The pulse rate when welding with pulsed GTAW (TIG welding) is:",
    answers: ["1 to 10 times per second;",
    "10 to 20 times per second;",
    "20 to 30 times per second;",
    "30 to 40 times per second."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the advantages of TIG Spot welding is that:",
    answers: ["the crater cracking is not a problem;",
    "the distortion is low;",
    "it increases the mechanical strength of the joint;",
    "it can be applied to join thicker workpieces."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In MAG welding, what is the effect of CO2 on the operational characteristics of the process?",
    answers: ["The fused zone gets bigger.",
    "Only spray metal transfer is possible, but with low spatter.",
    "Less spatter generation.",
    "Carbonization of the deposited metal takes place."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In MAG welding, what is the effect of CO2 on the operational characteristics of the process?",
    answers: ["Only spray metal transfer is possible, but with low spatter.",
    "Less spatter generation.",
    "Short circuiting metal transfer is the most commonly used and it is accompanied by higher spatter generation.",
    "Carbonization of the deposited metal takes place."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the functions of shielding gas in the GTAW (TIG welding) process is:",
    answers: ["to cool the air-cooled torch;",
    "to cool the tungsten electrode;",
    "to provide alloying elements to the weld pool;",
    "to ensure a proper metal transfer mode."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In TIG welding, which shielding gas do you consider appropriate to be indicated?",
    answers: ["High purity nitrogen for titanium.",
    "Helium for welding copper and its high-thickness alloys.",
    "A mixture of argon with carbon dioxide for welding carbon steel, as it ensures arc stability and improves heat transfer to the weld pool.",
    "Helium mixed with CO2 for martensitic stainless steels."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Only 10% of the flux can be recovered, recycled and reused, unlike in electroslag welding with almost 100% flux recovery.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized.",
    "Care is required to maintain a proper electrode alignment to the joint line.",
    "Only carbon steel can be welded."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Only direct current with positive electrode polarity (DCEP) can be used.",
    "Only carbon steel can be welded.",
    "The electrode tip and weld pool are “hidden” under the flux layer, which hampers the process control.",
    "It is not suitable for windy conditions."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["It is not suitable for windy conditions.",
    "A high volume of fumes is produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "Since the operator cannot see the welding being performed, he cannot confidently control the welding prosses.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Welded metal will be cooled at high rates as it receives a more concentrated heat input.",
    "Only direct current with positive electrode polarity (DCEP) can be used.",
    "Because the arc is not visible, tools such as seam trackers and jigs are needed.",
    "It is not suitable for extreme conditions (eg winds)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Welded metal will be cooled at high rates as it receives a more concentrated heat input.",
    "Only carbon steel can be welded.",
    "The process requires precise joint adjustment (sometimes applying auxiliary devices). Otherwise, flux may spill out of the joint.",
    "It is not suitable for extreme conditions (eg winds)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Only 10% of the flux can be recovered, recycled and reused, unlike in electroslag welding with almost 100% flux recovery.",
    "A high volume of fumes is produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "Flux is subject to contamination which can cause weld metal porosity.",
    "Only direct current with positive electrode polarity (DCEP) can be used."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Almost 100% of the flux is recovered, recycled and reused, unlike in electroslag welding with only 10% slag recovery.",
    "It's easy to be mechanized or automated.",
    "Welding in the overhead position is possible, provided that special devices and accessories are used to maintain the flux.",
    "Well suited for a wide variety of commonly used metals and alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Well suited for a wide variety of commonly used metals and alloys.",
    "The flux is recoverable, recyclable and reusable.",
    "Almost 100% of the flux is recovered, recycled and reused, unlike in electroslag welding with only 10% slag recovery.",
    "Especially suitable for welding thick sections made of cast iron."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Especially suitable for welding thick sections made of cast iron.",
    "It is suitable for surfacing applications (wear resistant coatings, corrosion resistant coatings for steels, …).",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint).",
    "Welding in the overhead position is possible, provided that special devices and accessories are used to maintain the flux."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Well suited for a wide variety of commonly used metals and alloys.",
    "Typically, operator manipulative skills are not involved.",
    "Welding in the overhead position is possible, provided that special devices and accessories are used to maintain the flux.",
    "SAW fluxes do not need any special treatment (e.g., drying)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Almost 100% of the flux is recovered, recycled and reused, unlike in electroslag welding with only 10% slag recovery.",
    "Allows arrangements with up to 5 electrodes, providing the filler metal in the same weld pool.",
    "Especially suitable for welding thick sections made of cast iron.",
    "Welding in the overhead position is possible, provided that special devices and accessories are used to maintain the flux."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Well suited for a wide variety of commonly used metals and alloys.",
    "Less demanding of the operator's psychomotor skills.",
    "This process allows welding of thin material (from 3 mm) and up to unlimited thickness, using multiple passes.",
    "Welding in the overhead position is possible, provided that special devices and accessories are used to maintain the flux."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The mechanical properties of a submerged arc welded joint will depend on:",
    answers: ["the type (chemical composition) of the electrode wire only;",
    "from the interaction of the electrode wire (chemical composition) with the flux (chemical composition and production method).",
    "the welding position;",
    "the electrode diameter and the flux granulometry."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Why is argon would be a better choice over helium in MIG/MAG welding?",
    answers: ["Argon allows for higher welding speeds.",
    "It facilitates arc ignition and ensures a more stable arc due to its lower ionization potential.",
    "Argon promotes arc voltage growth, thereby increasing the heat generated by the arc.",
    "It favours a better profile of the weld fusion area."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Indicate the correct statement regarding shielding gas in TIG welding of aluminium.",
    answers: ["Oxidizing mixtures are not used, as they would cause excessive oxidation of the weld pool.",
    "When welding thick plates, helium can be added to the argon to ensure the formation of the molten area.",
    "Although helium is a more expensive, its use instead of argon is justifiable, as it offers more efficient protection, which allows to drastically reduce the flow rates used.",
    "Ar-H2 mixtures can be used if you need better protection for the tungsten electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In gas welding/cutting, what is the difference between a Reverse Flow Check Valve (one-way valve) and a flame arrestor (Flashback Arrestor)?",
    answers: ["The one-way valve is a mechanical device and does not prevent the passage of flame.",
    "The one-way valve is mounted on the gas regulator, while the flame arrester valve is mounted on the torch.",
    "The most important is the Reverse Flow Check Valve (one-way valve).",
    "The Reverse Flow Check Valve is mounted on the acetylene line, while the flame arrester valve is installed on the oxygen line."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Welded metal will be cooled at high rates as it receives a more concentrated heat input.",
    "Only carbon steel can be welded.",
    "Limited to carbon steel and stainless steel and some nickel-based alloys.",
    "It is not suitable for extreme conditions (e.g., winds)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Only 10% of the flux can be recovered, recycled and reused, unlike in electroslag welding with almost 100% flux recovery.",
    "A high volume of fumes is produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "Limited to long straight welds or circumferential welds on rotated tubes and vessels.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Only carbon steel can be welded.",
    "A high volume of fumes is produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "Cast iron, Al alloys, Mg, Pb and Zn alloys cannot be welded by this process.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Only carbon steel can be welded.",
    "A high volume of fumes is produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "Requires inter-pass and post-weld slag removal.",
    "It cannot be used for surfacing because of deep penetration."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Welded metal will be cooled at high rates as it receives a more concentrated heat input.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized.",
    "Limited to thick materials.",
    "Formation of rough surfaces of the weld bead and undercuts generation."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Only carbon steel can be welded.",
    "A high volume of fumes is produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "May require weld joint backing to ensure full root penetration.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Welded metal will be cooled at high rates as it receives a more concentrated heat input.",
    "Only 10% of the flux can be recovered, recycled and reused, unlike in electroslag welding with almost 100% flux recovery.",
    "After being exposed to moisture, the SAW fluxes need to be dried out.",
    "Welding of high alloy steels is not possible."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Welded metal will be cooled at high rates as it receives a more concentrated heat input.",
    "It is not suitable for extreme conditions (e.g., winds).",
    "Selecting a wire/flux combination is more difficult than selecting covered electrodes, shielding gases or wires in the GMAW (MIG/MAG) process.",
    "Only carbon steel can be welded."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Welded metal will be cooled at high rates as it receives a more concentrated heat input.",
    "It is not suitable for extreme conditions (e.g., winds).",
    "Higher equipment cost compared to the GMAW process (MIG/MAG welding).",
    "Only carbon steel can be welded."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Well suited for a wide variety of commonly used metals and alloys.",
    "Almost no fume or light emission.",
    "Almost 100% of the flux is recovered, recycled and reused, unlike in electroslag welding with only 10% flux recovery.",
    "Fluxes for SAW do not need any special treatment (eg, redrying)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Welding in the overhead position is possible, provided that special devices and accessories are used to maintain the flux.",
    "It is well suited for welding thick sections.",
    "Almost 100% of the flux is recovered, recycled and reused, unlike in electroslag welding with only 10% slag recovery.",
    "Especially suitable for welding thick sections made of cast iron."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Especially suitable for welding thick sections made of cast iron.",
    "Extremely high metal deposition rates can be achieved.",
    "Porosity is impossible to occur (due to the degassing of the weld pool guaranteed by a long life of the weld pool).",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["This process allows welding of thin material (from 3 mm) and up to unlimited thickness, using multiple passes.",
    "The molten flux provides very suitable conditions for high heat to be generated and kept concentrated to weld thicker sections with deep penetrations.",
    "Almost 100% of the flux is recovered, recycled and reused, unlike in electroslag welding with only 10% flux recovery.",
    "Especially suitable for welding thick sections made of cast iron."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Well suited for a wide variety of commonly used metals and alloys.",
    "Due to a high heat concentration, considerably higher welding speeds can be achieved.",
    "Lower equipment cost compared to the GMAW process (MIG/MAG welding), because there is no supply of shielding gas.",
    "This process is the best for welding materials ticker than 3 mm and up to unlimited thickness using multiple passes."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Especially suitable for welding thick sections made of cast iron.",
    "Due to a high heat concentration and high welding speeds, welded joint distortion is low.",
    "Welding in the overhead position is possible, provided that special devices and accessories are used to maintain the flux.",
    "Almost 100% of the flux is recovered, recycled and reused, unlike electroslag welding with only 10% flux recovery."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Especially suitable for welding thick sections made of cast iron.",
    "Single pass welds can be made in heavy plates with conventional equipment.",
    "Almost 100% of the flux is recovered, recycled and reused, unlike in electroslag welding with only 10% flux recovery.",
    "Fluxes for SAW do not need any special treatment (e.g., redrying)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Almost 100% of the flux is recovered, recycled and reused, unlike in electroslag welding with only 10% flux recovery.",
    "A very smooth bead finishing can be obtained with very smooth transitions.",
    "Welding in the overhead position is possible, provided that special devices and accessories are used to maintain the flux.",
    "Especially suitable for welding thick sections made of cast iron."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Well suited for a wide variety of commonly used metals and alloys.",
    "Welding is carried out without spatter, fumes and sparks.",
    "Almost 100% of the flux is recovered, recycled and reused, unlike in electroslag welding with only 10% flux recovery.",
    "Fluxes for SAW do not need any special treatment (eg, redrying)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Especially suitable for welding thick sections made of cast iron.",
    "This process can be used for welding in areas exposed to relatively high winds.",
    "Welding in the overhead position is possible, provided that special devices and accessories are used to maintain the flux.",
    "Fluxes for SAW do not need any special treatment (eg, redrying)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The time duration for tungsten electrodes can be stored before use is:",
    answers: ["1 year;",
    "2 years;",
    "3 years;",
    "as indicated by the manufacturer."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the truth about the variables of the TIG process?",
    answers: ["The arc length (hence the arc voltage) is kept constant due to the use of a non-consumable electrode.",
    "Due to the use of a non-consumable electrode, the welding current does not vary regardless of the power source static characteristic used (Constant Current or Constant Voltage).",
    "Alternating current is never used in the TIG process, due to arc instability.",
    "The current value must be chosen according to the thickness of the part to be welded."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say about energy sources for arc welding: ",
    answers: ["It is possible to use some types of sources for more than one welding process (for example, for welding with coated electrodes and TIG welding).",
    "It is possible to use the same equipment (multiprocesses) for the MIG/MAG and TIG processes, but only if the TIG process is to work with direct current and wire feeding.",
    "A conventional MIG/MAG process power source is not suitable for the TIG process, which uses DCEP polarity.",
    "A conventional MIG/MAG process power source is not suitable for the TIG process as it is of Constant Current type."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say about energy sources for arc welding: ",
    answers: ["It is not possible to use the same power source for more than one welding process.",
    "It is possible to use the same equipment (multiprocesses) for the MIG/MAG and TIG processes, but only if the TIG process is to work with direct current and wire feeding.",
    "A conventional MIG/MAG process power source is not suitable for the TIG process, which uses DCEP polarity.",
    "A conventional MIG/MAG process power source is not suitable for the TIG process as it is of Constant Voltage type, while the TIG process needs a Constant Current type source."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say about energy sources for arc welding: ",
    answers: ["It is possible to use some types of power sources for more than one welding process (for example, for welding with covered electrodes and TIG welding).",
    "A conventional MIG/MAG process power source is not suitable for the TIG process as it is of Constant Current type.",
    "A conventional MIG/MAG process power source is not suitable for the TIG process, which uses DCEP polarity.",
    "A conventional MIG/MAG process power source is not suitable for the TIG process, as these processes use different types of current, the MIG/MAG process uses DC, while the TIG process needs AC."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the TIG process, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["It is not necessary to clean the carbon steel plates (even with scale), just enough to apply alternating current and they will be cleaned by the “cathodic cleaning” action.",
    "In TIG welding with filler metal feeding, the current value is a consequence of the adjustment of the wire feed speed.",
    "The shielding gas flow rate is directly proportional to the tungsten electrode diameter and it is not dependent on the current value (as the primary function of shielding gas is to protect the tungsten electrode).",
    "The electrode sharpening angle depends on the current level (smaller angles for lower currents)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the process whose principle of cutting is based on melting the metal to be cut:",
    answers: ["Water jet cutting.",
    "Oxyfuel gas cutting.",
    "High-speed mechanical cutting.",
    "Carbon arc cutting."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the process whose principle of cutting is based on melting the metal to be cut:",
    answers: ["Water jet cutting.",
    "Oxyfuel gas cutting.",
    "Plasma arc cutting.",
    "High-speed mechanical cutting."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true statement about the TIG (GTAW) process:",
    answers: ["In TIG welding with DCEN polarity, the electric arc is less stable than with DCEP polarity and the electrode suffers excessive wear.",
    "TIG welding with alternating current is used for welding austenitic stainless steels.",
    "In TIG welding torches, the nozzle cups should be as narrow as possible to provide adequate shielding gas density.",
    "In TIG welding with helium shielding gas, low arc voltage and better cleaning effect are produced."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true statement about the TIG (GTAW) process:",
    answers: ["In TIG welding with DCEN polarity, the electric arc is less stable than with DCEP polarity and the electrode suffers excessive wear.",
    "TIG welding with alternating current is used for welding austenitic stainless steels.",
    "In TIG welding torches, the nozzle cups must be wide enough to provide protection of the welding area by the gas used.",
    "In TIG welding with helium shielding gas, low arc voltage and better cleaning effect are produced."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true statement about the TIG (GTAW) process:",
    answers: ["In TIG welding with DCEN polarity, the electric arc is less stable than with DCEP polarity and the electrode suffers excessive wear.",
    "TIG welding with alternating current is used for welding austenitic stainless steels.",
    "In TIG welding with helium shielding gas, low arc voltage and better cleaning effect are produced.",
    "The TIG welding can be used for thin sheets with butt joints, edge joints, corner joints and lap joints."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true statement about the TIG (GTAW) process:",
    answers: ["The sharpening of the electrodes facilitates the heating of the electrode tip and, thus, favours the emission of electrons by thermionic effect, in addition to ensuring a more stable arc.",
    "In TIG welding with helium shielding gas, low arc voltage and better cleaning effect are produced.",
    "TIG welding with alternating current is used for welding austenitic stainless steels.",
    "In TIG welding with DCEN polarity, the electric arc is less stable than with DCEP polarity and the electrode suffers excessive wear."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true statement about the TIG (GTAW) process:",
    answers: ["The shielding gas flow rate is directly proportional to the tungsten electrode diameter and it is not dependent on the current value (as the primary function of shielding gas is to protect the tungsten electrode).",
    "In TIG welding with helium shielding gas, low arc voltage and better cleaning effect are produced.",
    "In TIG welding with hot wire, the wire is preheated by an electric current passing through it (resistance heating).",
    "In TIG welding with filler metal feeding, the current value is a consequence of the adjustment of the wire feed speed."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The electrode wire melting rate of the MIG/MAG process can be increased by:",
    answers: ["\"decreasing the energized length of the electrode (reducing the \"\"contact tip - workpiece\"\" distance).\"",
    "increasing the energized length of the electrode (electrode extension or stick-out), keeping the current constant.",
    "using electrode tip weaving.",
    "\"using the backhand (\"\"pulling\"\") welding technique.\""],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The electrode wire melting rate of the MIG/MAG process can be increased by:",
    answers: ["increasing the current (increasing the electrode wire feed speed), keeping the electrode stick-out (electrode extension) constant.",
    "\"decreasing the energized length of the electrode (reducing the \"\"contact tip - workpiece\"\" distance), keeping the current constant.\"",
    "using electrode tip weaving.",
    "\"using the backhand (\"\"pulling\"\") welding technique.\""],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding oxyfuel gas welding.",
    answers: ["\"A neutral flame is named \"\"neutral\"\" since, in most cases, it will not affect the chemical composition of the metal being welded.\"",
    "It is a low heat input process, but it becomes of a very high heat concentration process if the flame cone is brought close to the metal that is to be melted.",
    "The more oxygen in the gas mixture, the easier it is to weld reactive materials, as the M+O2 reaction is exothermic.",
    "The combustion of fuel gas (eg, acetylene) takes place only with oxygen from the atmosphere."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding oxyfuel gas welding.",
    answers: ["It is a low heat input process, but it becomes of a very high heat concentration process if the flame cone is brought close to the metal that is to be melted.",
    "Heat input and filler metal addition are controlled completely independently.",
    "The more oxygen in the gas mixture, the easier it is to weld reactive materials, as the M+O2 reaction is exothermic.",
    "The combustion of fuel gas (eg, acetylene) takes place only with oxygen from the atmosphere."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding oxyfuel gas welding.",
    answers: ["It is a low heat input process, but it becomes of a very high heat concentration process if the flame cone is brought close to the metal that is to be melted.",
    "The more oxygen in the gas mixture, the easier it is to weld reactive materials, as the M+O2 reaction is exothermic.",
    "The calorific power of the process is controlled by the size of the torch tip: the larger tip, the higher the oxygen and fuel gas flow and, consequently, the more heat will be generated.",
    "The combustion of fuel gas (eg, acetylene) takes place only with oxygen from the atmosphere."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Why would helium be preferred over argon in gas shielded arc welding?",
    answers: ["Its ionization energy is lower.",
    "It is cheaper.",
    "Higher welding speeds become possible.",
    "it is less reactive with the weld pool."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Why would helium be preferred over argon in gas shielded arc welding?",
    answers: ["Its ionization energy is lower.",
    "It offers greater penetration.",
    "It is cheaper.",
    "it is less reactive with the weld pool."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The tungsten electrode tip wears out quickly in TIG welding because of:",
    answers: ["an excessively high current for the electrode size;",
    "an excessively high voltage for the electrode size;",
    "a high shielding gas flow rate;",
    "an excessive torch tilt."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The tungsten electrode tip wears out quickly in TIG welding because of:",
    answers: ["an excessively high voltage for the electrode size;",
    "positive electrode polarity (DCEP) used;",
    "a high shielding gas flow rate;",
    "an excessive torch tilt."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A welding flame with excess of acetylene can result in:",
    answers: ["a carburization of the weld pool;",
    "an oxygen reduction in the weld pool;",
    "a decarburization of the weld pool;",
    "a neutralization of the weld pool, by removing O2 from the weld pool."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A welding flame with excess of acetylene can result in:",
    answers: ["a flame temperature increase;",
    "a flame temperature reduction;",
    "a neutralization of the weld pool, by removing O2 from the weld pool;",
    "a penetration increase."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the adjustment in the conventional MIG/MAG process, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["the current is a variable dependent on the wire feed speed and the contact tip-to-work distance;",
    "the arc voltage affects the short circuit frequency: the higher the voltage, the higher this frequency;",
    "the contact tip can be damaged if low arc voltage and high wire feed speed are used, even with a high contact tip-to-work distance;",
    "the short-circuiting metal transfer type can be obtained by adjusting the wire feed speed and keeping a high arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0"},
    {
    question:"When welding high carbon steels the pass most susceptible to cracking is:",
    answers: ["hot pass;",
    "root pass;",
    "filling pass;",
    "cover pass."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a method of increasing the yield strength of a metallic material:",
    answers: ["Cold working (causing hardening of the metal);",
    "Hot working (causing hardening of the metal);",
    "Warm working (causing hardening of the metal);",
    "Hot lamination (causing hardening of the metal);"],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following groups of gases is used in MIG/MAG welding of stainless steels?",
    answers: ["Argon, helium, hydrogen, oxygen and argon+25%CO2 mixtures.",
    "Argon, helium, pure CO2 and argon+hydrogen mixtures.",
    "Argon+oxygen and argon+CO2 mixtures.",
    "Helium+CO2 mixtures."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following groups of gases is used in FCAW of carbon steels?",
    answers: ["Argon, helium, hydrogen, oxygen and argon+25%CO2 mixtures.",
    "Argon, helium, pure CO2 and argon+hydrogen mixtures.",
    "Pure CO2 and argon+25% CO2 mixture.",
    "Helium+CO2 mixtures."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When increasing the carbon content of a steel:",
    answers: ["the probability of fragility problems is reduced;",
    "the probability of generation of fragility zones is increased;",
    "its ductility is increased;",
    "its corrosion resistance is increased."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What heat treatment can be applied to harden a steel only on its surface, maintaining inside toughness and ductility?",
    answers: ["Quenching.",
    "Normalizing.",
    "Tempering.",
    "Carburizing. "],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What heat treatment is characterized by keeping the workpiece at the austenitizing temperature for a while and then it is allowed to cool inside the furnace?",
    answers: ["Normalizing.",
    "Annealing.",
    "Tempering.",
    "Austempering."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What heat treatment is characterized by keeping the workpiece for a short duration at the austenitizing temperature and then it is allowed to cool in still air at room temperature?",
    answers: ["Quenching.",
    "Carburizing. ",
    "Normalizing.",
    "Annealing."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following heat treatments results in the softest steel microstructure?",
    answers: ["Annealing.",
    "Quenching.",
    "Solid carburizing.",
    "Liquid carburizing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"During normalizing, the recommended cooling method is:",
    answers: ["in still air;",
    "in water;",
    "in oil;",
    "in the furnace or under an insulating material."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which compound may be used to decrease impurities (e.g., S and P) in steels during steel making process?",
    answers: ["FeC3.",
    "SiO2.",
    "TiO2.",
    "CaCO3."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which element may be used as deoxidizing purpose in MAG welding of steels?",
    answers: ["Mn.",
    "Cu.",
    "C.",
    "Mg."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which element may be used as deoxidizing purpose in MAG welding of steels?",
    answers: ["Si.",
    "Cu.",
    "C.",
    "Mg."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which element may be used as deoxidizing purpose in MAG welding of steels?",
    answers: ["Al.",
    "Cu.",
    "C.",
    "Mg."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A material that has a high work hardening coefficient:",
    answers: ["will undergo large deformation prior to fracture;",
    "will display significant directionality in mechanical properties in the annealed condition;",
    "tends to be less sensitive to fast cooling rates experienced during the welding cycle;",
    "has a high capacity to increase its strength by plastic deformation."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the reasons that a multipass weld would normally be tougher than a single pass weld is because:",
    answers: ["heat from the posterior pass normalises the previous pass metal;",
    "some martensite is formed;",
    "heat from one pass increases the grain size of a previous pass;",
    "heat from the posterior pass reduces impurities in the metal of the previous pass;"],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the reasons that a multipass weld would normally be tougher than a single pass weld is because:",
    answers: ["heat from the posterior pass refines the grains of the previous pass metal;",
    "some martensite is formed;",
    "heat from one pass increases the grain size of a previous pass;",
    "heat from the posterior pass reduces impurities in the metal of the previous pass;"],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is hardening due to welding cycle considered undesirable?",
    answers: ["Because it causes deformation of the welded joint.",
    "Because it causes brittleness.",
    "Because it does not let diffusible hydrogen leave the metal of HAZ.",
    "Because it causes undesirable compression stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is hardening due to welding cycle considered undesirable?",
    answers: ["Because it causes deformation of the welded joint.",
    "Because it causes undesirable shrinkage stress.",
    "Because it does not let diffusible hydrogen leave the metal of HAZ.",
    "Because it causes undesirable compression stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What may be the reason for hot cracks in weld metal in carbon steel?",
    answers: ["Too low heat input.",
    "Lack of preheating.",
    "The S and P content of the weld metal is too high.",
    "High content of H2 in the weld metal."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following mechanisms can be used to increase the yield strength of a 0.2% C steel?",
    answers: ["Decreasing grain size.",
    "Precipitation hardening.",
    "Solid solution hardening",
    "Hardening by hot deformation."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following mechanisms can be used to increase the yield strength of a 0.2% C steel?",
    answers: ["Hardening by cold deformation.",
    "Precipitation hardening.",
    "Solid solution hardening",
    "Hardening by hot deformation."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The main purpose of normalizing is:",
    answers: ["less hardness than in the case of annealing;",
    "stress relieving;",
    "greater ductility than in the case of annealing;",
    "grain refinement."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The main purpose of normalizing is:",
    answers: ["less hardness than in the case of annealing;",
    "stress relieving;",
    "greater ductility than in the case of annealing;",
    "less brittle structure."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Weldability of low-alloy steels is assessed by:",
    answers: ["hardness of the weld metal (greater hardness means worse weldability);",
    "carbon equivalent;",
    "level of residual stresses in welded joint;",
    "compatibility of the base metal and filler metal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How it is possible to enhance the weldability of a steel?",
    answers: ["Using the highest heat input as possible.",
    "Using the lowest heat input as possible.",
    "Using preheating.",
    "Using PWHT."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"On a stress-strain diagram, we are usually looking for:",
    answers: ["yield strength and ultimate strength;",
    "slope of elastic part;",
    "strength variation during elongation;",
    "the hardness value."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Austenitic stainless steels according to ISO/TR 15608 are designated:",
    answers: ["SS;",
    "W08;",
    "8;",
    "1.8."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What areas of the welded joint of structural steels are susceptible to hydrogen cracks?",
    answers: ["Just the parent metal.",
    "The weld metal and the parent metal.",
    "The heat affected zone (HAZ) and the parent metal.",
    "The weld metal and the heat affected zone (HAZ)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which are the main physical differences between stainless steel and non-alloy steel that have a great influence on the behaviour of the welding process?",
    answers: ["The thermal expansion and thermal conductivity of the stainless steel are higher.",
    "The thermal expansion of the stainless steel is lower, whereas the thermal conductivity is higher.",
    "The thermal expansion of the stainless steel is higher and the thermal conductivity is lower.",
    "The melting point of the stainless steel is higher and the weld pool liquid metal is more viscous."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A backing gas of argon or helium is applicable:",
    answers: ["only for welding of austenitic stainless steel;",
    "only for welding of ferritic stainless steel;",
    "only for welding of martensitic stainless steel;",
    "for all kind of stainless steels."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Filler metals for stainless steels usually have:",
    answers: ["a higher content of chromium than the parent metal;",
    "a lower content of chromium than the parent metal;",
    "a lower content of nickel than the parent metal.",
    "the same content of chromium and nickel as the parent metal."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"After welding of stainless steels, it may be necessary to pickle the welded joint. Why?",
    answers: ["To remove a thick visible oxide scale from the surface.",
    "To show the surface imperfections by eliminating the oxide.",
    "To remove weld heat tinted layers from the surface of stainless steel fabrications and to obtain a smooth and shiny surface;",
    "To restore the chromium-rich oxide passive layer."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"After welding of stainless steels, it may be necessary to pickle the welded joint. Why?",
    answers: ["To remove a thick visible oxide scale from the surface.",
    "To show the surface imperfections by eliminating the oxide.",
    "To remove weld heat tinted layers and to improve the corrosion resistance of the weld and the heat affected zone;",
    "To restore the chromium-rich oxide passive layer."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What type of filler metal for welding an aluminium alloy shall be used?",
    answers: ["Filler metal with the same or slightly higher content of alloy elements than the parent metal.",
    "Always the same content of alloying elements as the parent metal.",
    "The type of filler metal to be used for welding an aluminium alloy depends on the oxidizing potential of the shielding gas.",
    "Filler metal with an addition of the oxygen to restore the protective oxide layer."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which welding processes are used for welding of copper?",
    answers: ["MMA(SMAW) and MAG welding.",
    "MMA(SMAW) and FCAW.",
    "MIG welding and TIG welding.",
    "MIG welding and FCAW."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The symbol for a gas mixture according to ISO 14175 is:",
    answers: ["GM;",
    "G-M;",
    "M;",
    "MG."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What may be a reason for using nitrogen as shielding gas in TIG welding?",
    answers: ["It can be used to weld martensitic stainless steels.",
    "It can be used to weld copper.",
    "It can be used to weld titanium.",
    "It can be used to weld nickel alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Can a copper clad alloy be successfully cut with the oxy-acetylene cutting process?",
    answers: ["Yes.",
    "No.",
    "Only with a powder injection torch.",
    "Only if the steel side is where the cut is started."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"During annealing, the recommended cooling method is:",
    answers: ["in air;",
    "in water;",
    "in oil;",
    "in the furnace or under an insulating material."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Thick material is prone to cracking because ...",
    answers: ["the heat affected zone is usually larger;",
    "it can cause a rapid quench rate;",
    "it accumulates a lot of heat;",
    "the thicker material is, the more critical points are originated for cracks to occur."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"During the normalizing, the steel is cooled down _______ (than) during the annealing.",
    answers: ["faster",
    "slower",
    "with the same rate as ",
    "faster or slower, depending on the metal thickness. "],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Preheating heavy sections to 250 °C will:",
    answers: ["eliminate residual stress.",
    "reduce cracking in root passes.",
    "prevent cracking in finishing runs.",
    "prevent distortion in the parent metal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Uniformity of the grain structure throughout a weldment is achieved by what heat treatment?",
    answers: ["Quenching.",
    "Normalizing.",
    "Stress relieving.",
    "Preheating."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following cannot be accomplished with a post heat treatment?",
    answers: ["Annealing.",
    "Normalizing.",
    "Stress relieving.",
    "Distortion control."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Quenching carbon steel produces which grain structure? ",
    answers: ["Coarse.",
    "Fine.",
    "BCC.",
    "FCC."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is a carbon equivalent used for?",
    answers: ["To determine the ferrite number of steels.",
    "To calculate the heat input.",
    "To determine the toughness of a welded joint.",
    "To assess the steel weldability."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The susceptibility to hot cracking is minimized by:",
    answers: ["adding to the weld deposit a higher content of Mn to avoid the FeS formation;",
    "a higher level of the assembly stiffness to prevent crack opening;",
    "applying lower heat input (e.g., lower welding speeds);",
    "higher depth to width ratios of the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The susceptibility to hot cracking is minimized by:",
    answers: ["reducing, as lower as possible, the stiffness of the weld joint;",
    "a higher level of the assembly stiffness to prevent crack opening;",
    "applying lower heat input (e.g., lower welding speeds);",
    "higher depth to width ratios of the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The susceptibility to hot cracking is minimized by:",
    answers: ["applying lower heat input (e.g., higher welding speeds);",
    "a higher level of the assembly stiffness to prevent crack opening;",
    "applying lower heat input (e.g., lower welding speeds);",
    "higher depth to width ratios of the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The susceptibility to a lamellar tearing:",
    answers: ["does not depend on the amount and the type of inclusions trapped in the base material;",
    "is a function of the amount and the type of segregated impurities contained in the base material;",
    "does not depend on the weld joint type;",
    "will decrease with the increasing of the weld volume in a full penetration T-Joints."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When a material is described as conditionally weldable?",
    answers: ["When the material strongly deforms during welding.",
    "When a material is not a metal (e.g., plastics, ceramics, ...).",
    "When only high skilled welders can succeed to weld that material.",
    "When, in addition to common welding procedures, also special procedures (preheating, thermal treatment, certain heat input etc.) are needed."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"If plates vary 6 mm or more in thickness, the thicker plate should be bevelled to the thickness of the thinner plate. The transition (slope) used should be:",
    answers: ["no steeper than 1 to 10;",
    "no steeper than 1 to 8;",
    "no steeper than 1 to 6;",
    "no steeper than 1 to 3;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which fillet weld geometry increases fatigue strength?",
    answers: ["Fillet weld with equal legs.",
    "Convex fillet weld.",
    "Flat faced fillet weld.",
    "Concave fillet weld."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"To counteract the contraction forces of weld metal as it cools you would:",
    answers: ["accelerate cooling;",
    "apply peening;",
    "keep the pieces securely fastened;",
    "keep the arc open over the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Increasing the bevel angle in preparing a joint to be welded will normally:",
    answers: ["Reduce distortion as the weld volume becomes more balanced on both sides of the joint's neutral line;",
    "Reduce distortion as the weld pool becomes shallower with less volume of molten metal.",
    "Have no influence on distortion, as the weld volume remains balanced on both sides of the joint's neutral line;",
    "Increase distortion as both the width and the volume of the upper part of the weld are increased."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Increasing the groove angle of the butt weld joint will normally:",
    answers: ["increase distortion as both the weld width and the weld metal volume from the weld face are increased;",
    "reduce distortion, as the direction of shrinkage stresses will be more perpendicular to the sheet surfaces;",
    "reduce distortion, as the weld volume becomes balanced on both sides of the joint's neutral line;",
    "have no influence on distortion, as the weld volume becomes balanced on both sides of the joint's neutral line."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"A 10 m long vessel is to have 10 equally spaced brackets installed on it. The first and last brackets are to be spaced 0,5 m from the ends of the vessel. What is the distance between the brackets?",
    answers: ["0,5 m.",
    "0,9 m.",
    "1,0 m.",
    "1,1 m."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Notches in a metal structure should be avoided as:",
    answers: ["they facilitate crack propagation under static loading, but not the crack initiation;",
    "they reduce the yield strength of the material;",
    "they facilitate the nucleation of cracks under cyclic/dynamic loading, but not the crack propagation;",
    "they worsen the aesthetics of structures."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the reasons below justifies the use of symbology standards in the drawings of welded structures?",
    answers: ["The ease of changing the joint type to suit the company facilities.",
    "Time saving in indicating welded joint details.",
    "The ease of dimensioning of welded joints.",
    "So that a technical drawing with welded joints created in one country can be understood in any other country."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the reasons below justifies the use of symbology standards in the drawings of welded structures?",
    answers: ["The ease of changing the joint type to suit the company facilities.",
    "Space saving in drawings.",
    "The ease of dimensioning of welded joints.",
    "So that a technical drawing with welded joints created in one country can be understood in any other country."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is an advantage resulting from the use of high strength steels in reticulated constructions:",
    answers: ["Increased resistance to high cycle fatigue;",
    "Reduction of susceptibility to brittle fracture;",
    "Better quality welds thanks to a better weldability of these steels;",
    "Reduction in construction weight by the possibility of using thinner profiles."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is an advantage resulting from the use of high strength steels in reticulated constructions:",
    answers: ["Increased resistance to high cycle fatigue;",
    "Reduction of susceptibility to brittle fracture;",
    "Better quality welds thanks to a better weldability of these steels;",
    "Increased load capacity for the same beam dimensions;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"This information is indicated on the tail of the reference symbol (according to ISO 2553):",
    answers: ["the welding process, the acceptance level, the working position;",
    "the welding process, the acceptance level, the number of similar welds;",
    "welding process, groove type, working position;",
    "the weld type, the level of acceptance, the working position."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What kind of deformations result in ductile fracture?",
    answers: ["Combination of plastic and elastic deformations.",
    "Elastic.",
    "Plastic.",
    "There is no deformation."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What kind of deformations result in brittle fracture?",
    answers: ["Combination of plastic and elastic deformations.",
    "Elastic.",
    "Plastic.",
    "There is no deformation."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"This is an example of dynamic/cyclic loading:",
    answers: ["the weight of the structural elements;",
    "sudden high velocity winds;",
    "a parked truck in the middle of a bridge;",
    "a layer of snow over the roof."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the fatigue loading conditions:",
    answers: ["Static fatigue (EF);",
    "Low-cycle fatigue (LCF);",
    "Intermediate cycle fatigue (ICF);",
    "Super high cycle fatigue (SHCF)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the fatigue loading conditions:",
    answers: ["Static fatigue (EF);",
    "Intermediate cycle fatigue (ICF);",
    "High-cycle fatigue (HCF);",
    "Super high cycle fatigue (SHCF)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following will usually produce the greatest amount of distortion?",
    answers: ["One pass in a square butt groove preparation.",
    "\"Two opposite passes on a double \"\"V\"\" (\"\"X\"\") butt groove preparation. \"",
    "\"Welding of a single \"\"U\"\" butt groove preparation.\"",
    "Two opposite passes in a square butt groove preparation."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What can cause porosity when welding with cellulosic covered electrodes?",
    answers: ["Excessively high current.",
    "Excessively low current.",
    "Excessively high welding speed.",
    "Excessively low welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which is the highest open circuit voltage (r.m.s.) allowed according to IEC 60974-1 for welding with alternating current under normal conditions?",
    answers: ["48 V",
    "55 V",
    "68 V",
    "80 V"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which is the highest open circuit voltage (r.m.s.) allowed according to IEC 60974-1 for welding with alternating current under increased electrical dangerous conditions?",
    answers: ["48 V",
    "55 V",
    "68 V",
    "80 V"],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Auxiliary mounting devices should preferably …",
    answers: ["prevent transverse weld shrinkage;",
    "prevent transverse weld shrinkage, but allow for angular deformation of the welded joint;",
    "prevent angular deformation of the welded joint, but allow for transverse weld contraction;",
    "prevent both transverse weld shrinkage and angular deformation of the welded joint."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"For welding stainless steel or aluminium without ventilation it is important to:",
    answers: ["work with a welder’s shield (mask) with air support.",
    "thoroughly clean the surface of the workpieces to be welded.",
    "use a welding mask with a built-in dust filter.",
    "use a welding mask with a built-in gas filter."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following measures can lead to a welding time reduction (t=25 mm, fillet weld of a T-joint, 316-L stainless steel, in overhead position)?",
    answers: ["To use the welding process 111 instead of the process 135.",
    "To use the welding process 135 instead of the process 111.",
    "To use the welding process 311 instead of the process 135.",
    "To use the welding process 141 instead of the process 135."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Reducing the bevel angle of the weld joint preparation will normally:",
    answers: ["increase distortion, as the contraction forces will assume the position most perpendicular to the groove walls;",
    "increase distortion as the weld pool becomes deeper;",
    "have no influence on distortion, as the weld volume remains balanced on both sides of the joint's neutral line;",
    "reduce distortion as both the width and volume of the weld at the weld joint face will be reduced."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"To counteract the contraction forces of weld metal as it cools you would:",
    answers: ["preheat.",
    "peen.",
    "add filler metal to the crater.",
    "keep the arc open over the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Auxiliary mounting devices (jigs and fixtures):",
    answers: ["are used to increase the rigidity of welded construction;",
    "shall not be removed right after welding, to avoid residual deformation;",
    "prevent angular deformation of the welded joint by the effects of metal contraction during welding;",
    "shall be removed immediately after welding to avoid residual stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What safety device is used on a shielding gas cylinder?",
    answers: ["Plastic rupture disc.",
    "Metal rupture disk.",
    "Plastic fuse plug.",
    "Metal fuse plug."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Proper ventilation when using GTAW (TIG welding) in confined spaces is necessary because:",
    answers: ["the argon shielding gas displaces the air out;",
    "the emitted fumes reduce visibility;",
    "the emitted fumes can be absorbed by the weld metal causing porosity;",
    "Argon in a certain concentration can explode."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"GTAW (TIG welding) arc radiation in the air will produce:",
    answers: ["CO (carbon monoxide);",
    "CO2 (carbon dioxide);",
    "O3 (ozone);",
    "SO2 (sulphur dioxide)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 141 P FW W11 wm t04 PB bs nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, TIG welding, plates, fillet weld, stainless steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, MIG welding, plates, butt weld, fine-grain structural steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, TIG welding, plates, butt weld, non-alloy steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, MIG welding, plates, fillet weld, non-alloy steel."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 141 P FW W11 wm t04 PB bs nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld with filler metal, material thickness = 4 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld without filler metal, material thickness = 4 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld without filler metal, material thickness = 4 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld with filler metal, material thickness = 4 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 141 P FW W11 wm t04 PB bs nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, horizontal vertical position.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, vertical upwards position.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, flat position.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, overhead position."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 141 P FW W11 wm t04 PB bs nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, welding from both sides, without backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, single side welding, without backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, welding from both sides, with backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, single side welding, without backing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Requalification of a Welding Procedure Specification (WPS) is required when:",
    answers: ["The essential variables exceed the pre-established limits;",
    "Non-essential variables are added to WPS;",
    "Supplementary variables are added to WPS;",
    "Both essential and non-essential variables exceed pre-established limits."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a technique for minimizing angular distortions when using arc welding:",
    answers: ["To use the lowest possible welding speed to avoid rapid cooling of the weld and thus minimizing the generation of thermal stresses;",
    "To increase the welding speed, thus reducing the volume of deposited metal;",
    "To increase the bevel angle of the weld joint preparation;",
    "\"Pre-set parts by a \"\"pre-distortion\"\" (in the opposite direction of the expected deformation) so that distortion occurring during welding will be used to achieve overall alignment and dimensional control.\""],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a technique for minimizing distortions when using arc welding:",
    answers: ["To use the lowest possible welding speed to avoid rapid cooling of the weld and thus minimizing the generation of thermal stresses;",
    "The joint that may have the greatest contraction on cooling should be welded first;",
    "To increase the welding speed, thus reducing the volume of deposited metal;",
    "To increase the bevel angle of the weld joint preparation;"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which condition must be fulfilled for detecting a discontinuity by liquid penetrant testing?",
    answers: ["A discontinuity must be open to the surface.",
    "The surface must be smooth.",
    "The surface must be in a flat or vertical position (there is no way to apply the penetrant in the overhead position).",
    "The opening of the discontinuity should be of the order of 0.1 - 0.3 mm to facilitate the capillary action of the penetrant."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Liquid penetrant testing (LP) method can be preferred to magnetic particle testing method to detect superficial discontinuities when the material is:",
    answers: ["Carbon steel, as the indications of the LP method are much clearer;",
    "Aluminium alloys, as this material is not ferromagnetic;",
    "Gray cast iron, as its irregular surface does not allow metallic particles to be applied;",
    "Ferritic stainless steels, as they are characterized by a high resistance to magnetic field flux."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Liquid penetrant testing (LP) method can be preferred to magnetic particle testing method to detect superficial discontinuities when the material is:",
    answers: ["Carbon steel, as the indications of the LP method are much clearer;",
    "Magnesium alloys, as this material is not ferromagnetic;",
    "Gray cast iron, as its irregular surface does not allow metallic particles to be applied;",
    "Ferritic stainless steels, as they are characterized by a high resistance to magnetic field flux."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Liquid penetrant testing (LP) method can be preferred to magnetic particle testing method to detect superficial discontinuities when the material is:",
    answers: ["Carbon steel, as the indications of the LP method are much clearer;",
    "Austenitic stainless steels, as this material is not ferromagnetic;",
    "Gray cast iron, as its irregular surface does not allow metallic particles to be applied;",
    "Ferritic stainless steels, as they are characterized by a high resistance to magnetic field flux."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Liquid penetrant testing (LP) method can be preferred to magnetic particle testing method to detect superficial discontinuities when the material is:",
    answers: ["Carbon steel, as the indications of the LP method are much clearer;",
    "Copper alloys, as this material is not ferromagnetic;",
    "Gray cast iron, as its irregular surface does not allow metallic particles to be applied;",
    "Ferritic stainless steels, as they are characterized by a high resistance to magnetic field flux."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"In which of the following welding processes is fume considered to be hazardous to health?",
    answers: ["MIG/MAG (GMAW) welding.",
    "TIG (GTAW) welding.",
    "Manual metal arc welding (with covered electrodes).",
    "Submerged arc welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"In which of the following welding processes is fume considered to be hazardous to health?",
    answers: ["MIG/MAG (GMAW) welding.",
    "TIG (GTAW) welding.",
    "Self-shielded flux cored arc welding.",
    "Submerged arc welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Welders qualified in accordance with ISO 9606 to weld 2.0 mm thick sheets are also qualified to weld sheets with thicknesses:",
    answers: ["2.5 and 3.0 mm;",
    "1.0 and 4.0 mm;",
    "1.5 and 3.0 mm;",
    "2.0 and 5.0 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Welders qualified in accordance with ISO 9606 to weld 5.0 mm thick sheets are also qualified to weld sheets with thicknesses:",
    answers: ["4.0 and 8.0 mm;",
    "3.5 and 12.0 mm;",
    "4.0 and 12.0 mm;",
    "4.5 and 15.0 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Welders qualified in accordance with ISO 9606 to weld 15.0 mm thick plates are also qualified to weld plates with thicknesses:",
    answers: ["5.0 and 10.0 mm;",
    "3.0 and 10.0 mm;",
    "4.0 and 20.0 mm;",
    "4.5 and 30.0 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following methods can be used to reduce the risks associated with fumes in MIG/MAG welding?",
    answers: ["General ventilation with air supply.",
    "Welding with open shop windows and doors.",
    "Use of mobile hoods with flexible ducts.",
    "Welding using pushing technique (in this case the plasma jet with the fumes will be directed away from the welder)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following methods can be used to reduce the risks associated with fumes in MIG/MAG welding?",
    answers: ["General ventilation with air supply.",
    "Welding with open shop windows and doors.",
    "Use of a torch that contains a smoke exhaust system.",
    "Welding using pushing technique (in this case the plasma jet with the fumes will be directed away from the welder)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a technique for minimizing angular distortions when welding T-joints:",
    answers: ["To use the lowest welding speed to avoid rapid cooling of the weld and thus minimizing the thermal stresses generation;",
    "To deposit welds from both sides of the joint at the same time;",
    "To weld on one side of the sheet only, with full penetration, which would ensure a balance of tensions on both sides;",
    "To withdraw the web plate from the base plate as much as possible. Thus, the fillet weld assumes the shape of the but one, minimizing angular distortion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a technique for minimizing angular distortions when welding T-joints:",
    answers: ["To use the lowest welding speed to avoid rapid cooling of the weld and thus minimizing the thermal stresses generation;",
    "To deposit chain or staggered intermittent fillet welds (instead of long continuous ones), using the backstep welding technique;",
    "To weld on one side of the sheet only, with full penetration, which would ensure a balance of tensions on both sides;",
    "To withdraw the web plate from the base plate as much as possible. Thus, the fillet weld assumes the shape of the but one, minimizing angular distortion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding aspects of occupational safety and health, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["Effectively protecting welding personnel is just a matter of making PPE available;",
    "Welding processes with gas shielding (MIG/MAG, TIG) do not produce fumes that are harmful to the welder's health, unlike the welding with Covered and Tubular Electrodes;",
    "Synthetic fabrics are the most recommended to be used as protection for the welder, as they are more comfortable.",
    "It is dangerous to carry out repair welding on a closed container in which flammable liquids have been stored. First of all, it is necessary to clean it (fill it with water or non-reactive gas, such as CO2 or N2);"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding aspects of occupational safety and health, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["Effectively protecting welding personnel is just a matter of making PPE available;",
    "Welding processes with gas shielding (MIG/MAG, TIG) do not produce fumes that are harmful to the welder's health, unlike the welding with Covered and Tubular Electrodes;",
    "Synthetic fabrics are the most recommended to be used as protection for the welder, as they are more comfortable.",
    "Among the main harmful environmental agents present in most welding processes, can be mentioned heat, excessive light and fumes."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding aspects of occupational safety and health, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["Effectively protecting welding personnel is just a matter of making PPE available;",
    "Welding processes with gas shielding (MIG/MAG, TIG) do not produce fumes that are harmful to the welder's health, unlike the welding with Covered and Tubular Electrodes;",
    "Synthetic fabrics are the most recommended to be used as protection for the welder, as they are more comfortable, but are more expensive than traditional leather.",
    "The hazards associated with confined space welding are fire, explosion and lack of oxygen."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding aspects of occupational safety and health, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["Effectively protecting welding personnel is just a matter of making PPE available;",
    "Welding processes with gas shielding (MIG/MAG, TIG) do not produce fumes that are harmful to the welder's health, unlike the welding with Covered and Tubular Electrodes;",
    "Synthetic fabrics are the most recommended to be used as protection for the welder, as they are more comfortable, but are more expensive than traditional leather.",
    "Correct welding posture minimizes the welder's inhalation of gases and fumes."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the economic factors of arc welding processes, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["Due to the higher currents used, the FCAW process has a higher cost of electricity per kg of deposited metal;",
    "The choice of welding position is very important to enable higher deposition rates, with flat welding position being the most recommended.",
    "The reduction of the welding operating cycle together with the increase of the deposition rate, guarantee a reduction of the welding time and consequently allow a greater productivity;",
    "In the GMAW process, the greater the stick-out for the same wire feed speed, the greater the deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding welding fumes, the following statement is correct:",
    answers: ["In processes 111, 114 and 136 more fumes come from the coating of the electrodes and from the tubular electrode flux than from the filler metal itself.",
    "The particles that make up the welding fumes, although small, are not remained in suspension for a long period, so the protection must be concentrated only in the region close to the welder.",
    "Welding processes with gas shielding do not produce harmful fumes, unlike the processes 111 and 114.",
    "Among all welding processes, the only TIG process does not produce fumes that are harmful to the welder's health."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding welding fumes, the following statement is correct:",
    answers: ["Fumes generated in processes 111, 114 and 136 contain a high proportion of the metals from the electrode coating and from the tubular electrode flux.",
    "The particles that make up the welding fumes, although small, are not remained in suspension for a long period, so the protection must be concentrated only in the region close to the welder.",
    "Welding processes with gas shielding do not produce harmful fumes, unlike the processes 111 and 114.",
    "Among all welding processes, the only TIG process does not produce fumes that are harmful to the welder's health."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding welding fumes, the following statement is correct:",
    answers: ["Fumes are solid particles that originate from welding consumables, the base metal and any protective layer on the base metal.",
    "The particles that make up the welding fumes, although small, are not remained in suspension for a long period, so the protection must be concentrated only in the region close to the welder.",
    "Welding processes with gas shielding do not produce harmful fumes, unlike the processes 111 and 114.",
    "Among all welding processes, the only TIG process does not produce fumes that are harmful to the welder's health."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"}
];